World War Two was just ending. World War Murphy is about to begin.
Murphy's War is a drama, war film directed by Peter Yates.
Murphy is the sole survivor of his crew, that has been massacred by a
German U-Boat in the closing days of World War II.
He is rescued, and ends up at a forgotten mission station near the
mouth of the Orinoco, and begins to plot his vengeance.
He wishes to sink the U-Boat by means of any method imaginable to him, and sets about to make the
courageous attempt, assisted by Louis, the administrator of the local oil company.
Murphy, played by Peter O'Toole.
Hayden, played by Siân Phillips.
Brezan, played by Philippe Noiret.
Lauchs, played by Horst Janson.
Ellis, played by John Hallam.
Voght, played by Ingo Mogendorf.
Murphy's War is an Eastmancolor 1971 Panavision war film
starring Peter O'Toole and Siân Phillips.
It was directed by Peter Yates, based on the 1969 novel by Max Catto.
The film's cinematographer was Douglas Slocombe.
The film is set in Venezuela during World War II and focuses on a stubborn survivor of a sunken merchant ship who is consumed in his
quest for revenge and retribution against the Nazi German submarine that sank his ship and slaughtered the survivors.
The film explores themes of submarine, world war
ii, revenge, crane, sole survivor.
The tone is emotional.